<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>bf174759-120b-457a-a919-124467f2732a</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Amstrad PC1512</Name>
    <NestedName>Amstrad PC1512</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Default</SortBy>
    <Notes>The Amstrad PC1512 was Amstrad's mostly IBM PC-compatible computer system, first manufactured in 1986. It was later succeeded by the PC1640.

Whereas IBM's PC (and almost all PC compatibles) had a power supply in a corner of the main case, the PC1512's power supply was integrated with that of its monitor. The monitor had sufficient venting to cool itself by convection, instead of needing a fan. The PC1512 was therefore quieter than other PCs. Rumours circulated that an Amstrad PC would overheat, and while existing owners would note that this did not happen, new buyers were discouraged. As a result, later models had a cooling fan integrated into the main case. Another example of rumour was the suggestion that there were issues with the 'unshielded' power supply in the monitor affecting an optional hard drive that could be installed at the back of the base unit and further that this would be solved by taping tin foil or aluminum foil over the back of the base unit or the bottom of the monitor to shield the hard drive.

Amstrad licensed both MS-DOS 3.2 and Digital Research DOS Plus, which was largely compatible with MS-DOS and included some features from CP/M and the ability to read CP/M disks. Only one of these operating systems could be used at a time. They also licensed the GEM windowing system, which supported the customized CGA hardware of the 1512.

The PC1512 was followed by the PC1640, which had 640 KB of RAM and an EGA-compatible graphics chipset (though only the ECD model could display all EGA modes). Either model shipped with one or two 5¼-inch floppy drives, and optionally a hard drive (either 10 or 20 MB). The PC1640 also allowed replacing the internal graphics adapter with a 8bit ISA VGA graphics expansion board, which made it more versatile than the PC1512.

Both the PC1512 and the PC1640 could be upgraded with a NEC V30 CPU, that increased and added 80186 instruction set compatibilities, and by adding an Intel 8087 mathematical coprocessor. Upgraded with the FPU, the PC1512 and PC1640 did outperform later PC architectures (i.e. 80286 w/o FPU) in numerical operations which was highly useful for CAD and numerical calculations. Lotus 1-2-3 and Matlab supported the 8087. A performance benchmarks as conducted with Checkit compares the different models and configurations of the PC1512 and PC1640, with that of a fast 80286.

Amstrad also attempted to expand its market share by selling computers in the United States. In the US the PC1512 was marketed as the PC6400 and included a 20 MB hard drive and the RAM upgrade to 640 KB. The PC1512 was also sold as the Sinclair PC500.</Notes>
    <VideoPath>Z:\Videos\Platforms\Amstrad CPC (2).mp4</VideoPath>
    <ImageType />
    <Category />
    <LastGameId />
    <BigBoxView />
    <BigBoxTheme />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>false</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Amstrad PC1512</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
    <LocalDbParsed>false</LocalDbParsed>
    <Developer />
    <Manufacturer />
    <Cpu />
    <Memory />
    <Graphics />
    <Sound />
    <Display />
    <Media />
    <MaxControllers />
    <Folder />
    <VideosFolder />
    <FrontImagesFolder />
    <BackImagesFolder />
    <ClearLogoImagesFolder />
    <FanartImagesFolder />
    <ScreenshotImagesFolder />
    <BannerImagesFolder />
    <SteamBannerImagesFolder />
    <ManualsFolder />
    <MusicFolder />
    <ScrapeAs />
    <LastSelectedChild />
    <AndroidThemeVideoPath />
    <HideInBigBox>false</HideInBigBox>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>d33ed2ed-224e-45c1-9bb7-98ad3ab3ea3f</GameId>
    <GameTitle>Amstrad PC1512 Keyboard</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>pc1512kb.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>0</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>19bd39e6-9d31-44c6-9c9c-c2296d3db23b</GameId>
    <GameTitle>Amstrad PC1512 mouse</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>pc1512_mouse.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>1bc8e7fa-a609-4b32-8e03-78b81505e670</GameId>
    <GameTitle>Amstrad PC1512 mouse port</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>pc1512_mouse_port.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>2</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>92ae0e67-2417-48a6-ba9a-71fbad458393</GameId>
    <GameTitle>ISA8_CGA_PC1512</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>cga_pc1512.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>3</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>c714ac1a-0c32-475b-8d89-7a7c14c3358d</GameId>
    <GameTitle>PC1512</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>PC1512 (New Way Cracking).dsk</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Amstrad CPC</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>4</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>34d097ce-f4b5-4252-886a-031beeaf415f</GameId>
    <GameTitle>PC1512 SD</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>pc1512.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>5</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>fa66b376-9f6e-41d6-a886-19e07f3e32e2</GameId>
    <GameTitle>PC1640 SD</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>pc1640.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>6</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
</LaunchBox>