<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>87d84bc5-dcbf-494b-8dac-8d82ec57336b</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Arcade Midway Classics</Name>
    <NestedName>Midway Classics</NestedName>
    <SortBy />
    <Notes>Midway Games was an American video game developer and publisher. Its franchises included Spy Hunter, Rampage, Mortal Kombat, NBA Jam, Cruis'n, and NFL Blitz. Midway also acquired the rights to video games that were originally developed by Williams Electronics and Atari Games, such as Defender, Joust, Robotron 2084, Gauntlet, and the Rush series.

The company's predecessor Midway Manufacturing was founded in 1958, as an amusement game manufacturer. In 1973 it moved into the interactive entertainment industry, developing and publishing arcade video games. The company scored its first mainstream hit with the U.S. distribution of Space Invaders in 1978. Midway was purchased and re-incorporated in 1988 by WMS Industries Inc. After years as a leader in the arcade segment, Midway moved into the growing home video game market beginning in 1996, the same year that it made its initial public offering of stock. In 1998 WMS spun off its remaining shares of Midway. Midway was ranked the fourth largest-selling video game publisher in 2000.</Notes>
    <VideoPath />
    <ImageType />
    <Category />
    <LastGameId />
    <BigBoxView />
    <BigBoxTheme />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>true</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle />
    <IsAutogenerated>true</IsAutogenerated>
    <LocalDbParsed>false</LocalDbParsed>
    <Developer />
    <Manufacturer />
    <Cpu />
    <Memory />
    <Graphics />
    <Sound />
    <Display />
    <Media />
    <MaxControllers />
    <Folder />
    <VideosFolder />
    <FrontImagesFolder />
    <BackImagesFolder />
    <ClearLogoImagesFolder />
    <FanartImagesFolder />
    <ScreenshotImagesFolder />
    <BannerImagesFolder />
    <SteamBannerImagesFolder />
    <ManualsFolder />
    <MusicFolder />
    <ScrapeAs />
    <LastSelectedChild />
    <AndroidThemeVideoPath />
    <HideInBigBox>false</HideInBigBox>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistFilter>
    <Value>Arcade</Value>
    <FieldKey>Platform</FieldKey>
    <ComparisonTypeKey>EqualTo</ComparisonTypeKey>
  </PlaylistFilter>
  <PlaylistFilter>
    <Value>Midway</Value>
    <FieldKey>Publisher</FieldKey>
    <ComparisonTypeKey>Contains</ComparisonTypeKey>
  </PlaylistFilter>
</LaunchBox>