<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>09789baf-7f57-49b6-adc0-bdc2eaa4eca6</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Arcade Sega OutRun</Name>
    <NestedName>Arcade Sega OutRun</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Default</SortBy>
    <Notes>Based on the System 16
Second generation Super Scaler board; able to use sprite scaling to simulate 3D using Super Scaler technology
Designed because Yu Suzuki was unable to make Out Run on existing technology at the time.

Sega's OutRun hardware was released in 1986 with the driving game OutRun. It is a successor to their Hang-On hardware, making it the second in Sega's Super Scaler series of three-dimensional arcade hardware. It was succeeded by the Sega X Board in 1987.

The OutRun hardware, like the Hang-On hardware, has specifications similar to those of the System 16, with the addition of a second 68000 processor and a separate video board which allowed for an extra graphics layer for the road as well as sprite/texture scaling capabilities. The OutRun hardware can do everything the Hang-On hardware can do, but its processors are clocked higher (allowing for quicker calculations), it has more memory and faster bandwidth, and the video board's capabilities have been expanded, capable of drawing two roads (the Hang-On hardware can only draw one) and rendering sprites/textures using a framebuffer system with a higher fillrate (the Hang-On hardware used a line-buffer system). At the time, the OutRun hardware was a very powerful but expensive arcade board, with arcade operators advised to charge twice as many credits than for regular arcade machines.

Three games made use of the hardware, all of which are driving games. However, only OutRun and Turbo OutRun are truly for this hardware, as Super Hang-On was also released for the Hang-On hardware in a mostly identical form.</Notes>
    <VideoPath>Videos\Platforms\Sega Out Run.mp4</VideoPath>
    <BigBoxTheme />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>true</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Arcade Sega OutRun</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>981f8f4e-85b1-4e41-93a7-2513defc1fe7</GameId>
    <LaunchBoxDbId>7874</LaunchBoxDbId>
    <GameTitle>Out Run</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>mt_orun.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>-1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistFilter>
    <Value>segaorun.cpp</Value>
    <FieldKey>Source</FieldKey>
    <ComparisonTypeKey>EqualTo</ComparisonTypeKey>
  </PlaylistFilter>
</LaunchBox>