<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>94db12b7-e2e7-4b25-a891-1589bdccfc3f</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Published by Sony</Name>
    <NestedName>Published by Sony</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Platform</SortBy>
    <Notes>Sony Interactive Entertainment (SIE) is a multinational video game and digital entertainment company wholly owned by Japanese conglomerate Sony Corporation. The SIE Group is made up of three legal corporate entities, which operate under a single global leadership: Sony Interactive Entertainment LLC (SIE LLC), based in San Mateo, California, United States and the global headquarters, Sony Interactive Entertainment Inc. (SIE Inc.), based in Minato, Tokyo, Japan, and Sony Interactive Entertainment Europe Ltd (SIEE Ltd.), based in London, United Kingdom.[2] Tokyo-based SIE Inc. was originally founded as Sony Computer Entertainment Inc. (SCEI or SCE) in November 1993 to handle Sony's venture into video game development for the PlayStation systems. SIE LLC was established in San Mateo in April 2016 and is managed through Sony's American hub, Sony Corporation of America.

Since the launch of the original PlayStation console in 1994, the company has been developing PlayStation home video game consoles, accessories and services lineup. The company expanded from Japan into North America and Europe, where it founded the branches Sony Computer Entertainment America (SCEA) in May 1995 (in Foster City, California) and Sony Computer Entertainment Europe (SCEE) in July 1995 (in Liverpool). The company quickly became Sony's main resource for research and development in video games and interactive entertainment. In April 2016, SCE and Sony Network Entertainment International was restructured and reorganized into Sony Interactive Entertainment, carrying over the operations and primary objectives from both companies. The same year, SIE LLC was established, with its headquarters in San Mateo, California.

Sony Interactive Entertainment handles the research and development, production, and sales of both hardware and software for the PlayStation video game systems. SIE is also a developer and publisher of video game titles, and operates several subsidiaries in Sony's largest markets: North America, Europe and Asia. By August 2018, the company had sold more than 525 million PlayStation consoles worldwide.</Notes>
    <VideoPath>Videos\Platforms\Sony Playstation.mp4</VideoPath>
    <LastGameId>4a943d5f-f83f-4fc0-88cd-f2f7f56ca430</LastGameId>
    <BigBoxTheme />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>true</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Published by Sony</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>37f80b00-6442-4343-97c9-3144e939ed16</GameId>
    <GameTitle>2 Games in 1!: Archer Maclean's Mercury &amp; Mercury Meltdown USA</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>2 Games in 1! - Archer Maclean's Mercury &amp; Mercury Meltdown USA.iso</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Sony PSP</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>-1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistFilter>
    <Value>sony</Value>
    <FieldKey>Publisher</FieldKey>
    <ComparisonTypeKey>Contains</ComparisonTypeKey>
  </PlaylistFilter>
</LaunchBox>