<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>3d5a35c5-7d72-4315-bf27-3aa8956520bf</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Sony SMC-777 OS</Name>
    <NestedName>Sony SMC-777 OS</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Default</SortBy>
    <Notes>Sony began selling the SMC-777 (three-seven) personal computer in November 1983. Aimed for the home market, it came with a built-in 3.5-inch floppy disk drive. Designed to be used without needing any special knowledge, the SMC-777 could be operated by inserting a floppy disk with the appropriate software program into the computer and selecting the required functions from a screen menu with the cursor keys. The SMC-777 came with an original disk containing simple programming languages, software, and games to familiarize users with computers and get them interested in programming while having fun.

The SMC-777 had the following features.

1. The SMC-777 came with Sony's own Sony Filer operating system. Software could be selected and run through simple menu selections.
2. The SMC-777 came with a floppy disk containing eight software applications, including a basic programming language with function-based calculations, an educational programming language, and games.
3. The enhanced color graphics could make use of 16 colors, with the addition of eight intermediate colors to the basic eight colors of the SMC-70. The optional color palette board made it possible to design graphics with 16 colors chosen from a 4,096-color palette.</Notes>
    <VideoPath>Videos\Platforms\Sony SMC-777.mp4</VideoPath>
    <BigBoxTheme />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>true</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Sony SMC-777 OS</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>609bd2c4-b6cb-4da8-967d-44e24ea1a993</GameId>
    <GameTitle>SMC-777</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>smc777.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>-1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistFilter>
    <Value>smc777.cpp</Value>
    <FieldKey>Source</FieldKey>
    <ComparisonTypeKey>EqualTo</ComparisonTypeKey>
  </PlaylistFilter>
</LaunchBox>