<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>2b55f793-7a27-46ff-9365-71807c22a1c2</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Timetop Game King</Name>
    <NestedName>Timetop Game King</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Default</SortBy>
    <Notes>GameKing is a brand of handheld game consoles, designed and developed by Timetop in 2003, for the Hong Kong consumer market. The brand has three consoles, the GameKing I, the GameKing II and the GameKing III. A fourth console, the Handy Game, was produced by Timetop and shares some branding, but otherwise has little to do with the GameKing franchise.

The original GameKing console is an 8-bit handheld game console. It is based on a 65C02 CPU running at 6.0 MHz. It is fashioned to look like Nintendo's Game Boy Advance and comes in a wide array of vivid pastel colours, either opaque or transparent, and uses two AAA size batteries. The original GameKing lacks a backlit screen, a feature which has been added in its "successor", the GameKing II.

The consoles have above-average sound circuitry capable of multi-channel music and digital sound playback, but a comparably low quality greyscale LCD screen, only supporting four shades of grey and having a very low (48 by 32 pixels) resolution, combined with a slow refresh rate, poor readability and adjustments, compared to the original Game Boy.

Games can be compared to some of the earlier built-in cell phone games (pre Java games), while their playing speed (scrolling etc.) and audio is far superior (multi-channel music and digitized samples and voices are quite common in GameKing games).</Notes>
    <VideoPath />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>false</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Timetop Game King</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
    <LocalDbParsed>false</LocalDbParsed>
    <HideInBigBox>false</HideInBigBox>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>e58710ff-d7ba-4c94-b479-eca5c86b615c</GameId>
    <GameTitle>GameKing 3</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>gamekin3.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>0</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>0e4c16d2-10ed-4bf5-b044-88093079aea7</GameId>
    <GameTitle>GameKing GM-218</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>gameking.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
</LaunchBox>