<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<LaunchBox>
  <Playlist>
    <PlaylistId>c9613e5e-1edb-48d9-bc4a-ba6df26cdfab</PlaylistId>
    <Name>Triumph-Adler Alphatronic OS</Name>
    <NestedName>Triumph-Adler Alphatronic OS</NestedName>
    <SortBy>Default</SortBy>
    <Notes>Triumph was originally Triumph-Adler - the merger company of the 2 typewriter manufacturers Triumph and Adler, to which Triumph (which also produced mechanical calculators and sewing-machines) was the bigger one. Later they got US-typewriter Royal merged into it and had the best years between 1975 and 1988, when they even build competiting machines to IBM System /34 and /36 ... but they did neither understand nor learn the business and ran out of the financial power.

The technical part of TA is today a subsidary of Olivetti which tells it all about the downfall of TA. The operational part is a Holding in Nuremberg, which deals with offices, buildings and health-care.

The Alphatronic was mainly sold in Germany and was intended as a 'hybrid' Business / Home machine. For Business it was sold as either a 'dumb' Terminal or as a stand-alone Word Processor 'package' (consisting of base unit, WP Cartridge and (Centronics) printer.

For home the base unit had a 'built in' Basic ROM - it was also available with either a single or dual Floppy Disks (which included CP/M and Disk basic).

It never sold very well in either market - it was much too expensive for home use.

Thanks to its Z80 CPU, the Alphatronic PC can run CP/M and quite a few software packages available for it. There were two external disk-drives available: F1 and F2. F1 had the controller built-in. You had to have F1 to use F2, the second one.

Sometimes, the Alphatronic PC was sold as a complete wordprocessing package with a daisy-wheel printer (Triumph-Adler TR-170) and a word-processing cartridge inserted into the ROM-pack slot (top left part of the case).

Towards the end of it's life, the British Company, MATMOS sold off the final 'batch' or single &amp; dual floppy packages together with a RGB-PAL convertor box.</Notes>
    <VideoPath />
    <IncludeWithPlatforms>false</IncludeWithPlatforms>
    <AutoPopulate>false</AutoPopulate>
    <SortTitle>Triumph-Adler Alphatronic OS</SortTitle>
    <IsAutogenerated>false</IsAutogenerated>
    <LocalDbParsed>false</LocalDbParsed>
  </Playlist>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>a003d561-997d-4955-85a2-17d78e7f320f</GameId>
    <GameTitle>alphatronic P2</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>alphatp2.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>0</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>284143b2-fd7d-4312-b18c-774c11e90cc8</GameId>
    <GameTitle>alphatronic P3</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>alphatp3.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>1</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>4153e8b4-77ec-4c8f-becd-a8d69178345c</GameId>
    <GameTitle>Alphatronic PC</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>alphatro.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>2</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
  <PlaylistGame>
    <GameId>1f8f43c8-ff2f-499c-a8be-1bd5bc3e31c3</GameId>
    <GameTitle>alphatronic PC-16</GameTitle>
    <GameFileName>alphatpc16.zip</GameFileName>
    <GamePlatform>Arcade</GamePlatform>
    <ManualOrder>3</ManualOrder>
  </PlaylistGame>
</LaunchBox>